# Robert J Phillips

Accomplished product leader with foundational expertise in analytics, product lifecycle management, and operations across the risk management, finance, and technology sectors. My mission is to create transformative user experiences and execute high-impact strategies to deliver measurable business outcomes.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Product Manager, Assistant Vice President Lockton | New York, NY | Oct 2023 - Present

- Global Analytics Engagement leader for new product creation
- Led all phases Ideation, Discovery, Planning, Design, Execution, QA, Launch - of an industry-leading Exposure Management Product, increasing insurance broker operational efficiency by 4x
- Ensured successful product development, deployment, and adoption through continuous engagement with Product Stakeholders and Operational leaders
- Trusted advisor for technology strategy and practical solutions

## **Product Owner**

Lockton | New York, NY | Sep 2022 - Sep 2023

- End-to-end owner of enterprise data products, including ELT processes and output experiences, supporting 550+ associates and producers across the \$3B enterprise.
- Managed multiple vendor teams of 10+ responsible for supporting and enhancing Lockton's data products.
- Subject matter expert for data extraction and standardization processes, providing critical insights to enhance product offerings.

# Senior Business Intelligence Analyst

Lockton | Denver, CO | Mar 2021 - Dec 2022

- Developed external-facing dashboards and reports for clients, helping them visualize and understand insurance programs, associated costs, and risk mitigation strategies.
- Depended upon to engage clients through data storytelling and tailored training, driving external-facing product adoption.

## **Data Analyst**

CRIF Corporation | Denver, CO | Aug 2017 - Mar 2021

- Primary point of contact for business trends, collaborating closely with executive leaders to develop market arbitrage strategies.
- Developed ROI models to project client profitability
- Delivered decisioning analysis to C-Suite clientele, resulting in a 178% increase in AI decisioning volume.
- Spearheaded the implementation of a Paperless Data Extraction system, reducing processing time from 24 hours to 20 minutes.
- Wrote complex SQL queries to gather and report data for daily operations and sales reporting.

## **Contact Information**

Phone: (209) 338-4300

Email: rjphillips95@gmail.com LinkedIn: robertphillips95

www.linkedin.com/in/robertphillips95

## **SKILLS**

Product Design

Product Execution

**Problem Solving** 

Cross Team Collaboration

Storytelling

Customer-Centric Mindset

Client Engagement

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of California, Santa Barbara — Mathematics

B.S. 2013 - 2017

# **PROJECTS**

# **Sports Analytics API**

NHL, NCAAB, and NFL data api integration aimed at analyzing trends and projecting performance.

# **Personal Cloud Storage**

Secure home cloud storage solution for personal files.

## **Awards**

# **Presidential Mentorship**

Hand selected by president of CRIF Corporation to participate in mentorship program.